[Episode 4]
He is handsome.
Good-looking.
Elegant.
Charming.
Refined.
Gentle-manlike.
I've never ever met such a handsome man here.
Look at how elegantly he eats the mutton!
He must be from Jiangnan.
He looks just like a refined gentleman
stepping out of a painting.
He looks so refined while eating.
A good-looking person
makes everything they do pleasing to the eye.
I'll go invite him for a drink.
I'll go.
- I'll go.
Bring my treasured grape wine
to that gentleman.
- Please, young master.
Please, ladies.
Come back!
No need to give him the wine.
Ms. Yan.
I was sorry to help Jiang Mei Er before.
Please tell your father
not to cut off our business.
My father said
that if I can't restore our business,
he will break my legs.
Please mercifully forgive me this once.
It's too late.
When you helped Jiang Mei Er,
you should have thought of the consequences.
I was wrong. I made a stupid mistake.
Show mercy, please!
Get out! You're affecting my business.
Yan Fu Zhi,
are you really going to drive me to my death?
Jiang Mei Er was indeed right.
You are also an evil woman,
just like Meng Ting Hui.
Both of you are ruthless and heartless.
How dare you insult Meng like that!
Today, I'll make you know what you'll get
after offending an evil and ruthless woman.
Get up!
Help!
If you set foot in Bofeng again,
I'll beat you hard!
Eat your food!
You're beautiful yet so fierce and shrewish.
You should
discipline your husband moderately.
He isn't my husband. He's unfit for it.
You're handsome yet brainless.
All you know is to show off like a peacock
when you see a girl.
Miss, what you said are hurtful.
I was just kindly trying
to break up the fight.
However, you have such a fiery temper.
No wonder that gentleman
would rather get beaten than marry you.
What? You get out too!
Shut up, you playboy!
It's none of your business!
Why can you make me leave?
I am the boss of Bofeng.
Now, get out!
Get out!
You...
You really are shrewish and fierce.
[Bofeng]
You are not allowed to come here again.
Why can't I--
Huang, why are you here?
The young master ordered me to find you.
Wait a moment, I need to reason with her.
How dare she hit me with an abacus!
Mr. Shen, you really can't mess with her.
She's just a businesswoman.
What's so special about her?
She is Meng Ting Hui's best friend.
She even slashed at the young master
with a knife before.
You mean our young master?
Even so, can't I just stay away?
Wait for me!
[Shazhou Government Office]
Sir, this way, please.
As per Mr. Shen's instructions,
we've arranged your accommodations
in the east wing of the government office.
I will lead you there now.
Which Mr. Shen are you talking about?
That is me.
Father.
It's your handsome, refined,
and graceful son.
Shen Zhi Shu.
Zhi Shu, you're here.
My good son! Turn around.
Let me take a good look at you.
How dare you!
You are so bold!
How dare you assist His Majesty
in leaving the palace!
You nearly endanger our Shen family!
I'm just loyally serving His Majesty.
Are you doing so?
Our Shen family has been unblemished
for generations.
How did I have a reckless son like you?
- Father.
- Stop running!
Father, I have an official position now!
Beating a court official
is punishable by law!
I'll beat you to death first
and then apologize to the late Emperor!
Stop right there!
Father!
Put down your weapon immediately!
If you kill me accidentally,
there will be no one
to bury you after you die.
How dare you curse your own father!
You're done for!
Don't move!
Stop hiding!
This is infuriating!
Your Majesty.
If you don't show up right now,
Zhi Shu will be beaten to death.
No rush.
I haven't seen such a warm scene
since I ascended the throne.
- You unfilial son!
- Father!
- I really--
- Don't hide!
Stop watching!
If you don't show up, I'll be dead!
Calling for help? I'll beat him too!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
You're as impressive as ever.
Every strike is still accurate.
Father, you kneel quite nimbly,
much more adept than beating me.
Please rise quickly.
It was my own decision to leave the palace.
Zhi Shu just did as I commanded.
If you blame him, I'll feel guilty.
Since Your Majesty speaks for him,
I will forgive him this time.
What you did in Shazhou
is an open yet wise move.
It not only stopped the misuse
of military equipment,
but also brilliantly checked Lord Xu.
You're as wise as the late Emperor.
You flatter me.
I have observed secretly for a long time.
I deeply feel the tense situation
in the court.
Your Majesty has few capable people
by your side.
It is urgent to cultivate trusted confidants.
Pei Jing He, Left Assistant Minister
of the Ministry of War,
is virtuous, talented, and intelligent.
But he is ostracized
because he hates Liu Ren's autocratic ways,
with no real power.
Now he can be used by Your Majesty.
Although you're outside the court,
you know the overall situation very well.
The world is like a chessboard.
Your Majesty is the player.
Though I've retired,
I'm willing to be Your Majesty's chess piece
for the stability of the nation.
Now, among the six ministries,
Xu Ting already controls four.
The talented men selected
through the past imperial examinations
have all worked for him.
I now have no choice but to seek talent
from the Imperial Exam for Women,
which he disdains to interfere with.
Your Majesty, I have one more thing to say.
As the saying goes,
a new emperor brings in new ministers.
The power of the two chancellors
is growing day by day.
If these two work together,
Your Majesty may find it hard to counter.
Now Xu Ting is at the peak of his power,
arousing Gu Qin's discontent.
Your Majesty can turn this to your advantage.
I need not elaborate on checks and balances.
[Gu Mansion]
Is this painting's brushwork insufficient,
so it failed to be ranked top-grade?
No.
It only depicts still life
and lacks liveliness.
Not so.
Zhi Li is here.
Sir.
This painting is
of a dusk scene of the late spring.
However, the flowers, trees,
and misty clouds in the painting
are too bright and gaudy,
thus losing the sense of reality.
In that case,
it will lose a vivid artistic flavor.
The same goes for a person.
If a person is false, they are rotten inside.
Zhi Li, have a seat.
Zhi Li understands the teacher best.
Zhi Li is quick-witted and careful.
In the Imperial Exam for Women,
with your talent, not to mention passing,
even winning the top spot
will not be difficult.
Sir, you passed the imperial examination
with high honors back then.
When you first entered the Ministry of Works,
you impressed the court
with your Water Control Strategy.
Once implemented,
it solved the water disasters in Jiangnan.
You relieved the people's worries.
I'm willing to follow you,
become a court official,
and work with you.
But yesterday, my father said
that Lord Xu strongly
opposes the Imperial Exam for Women.
Even if women enter the court,
they cannot rise above the sixth rank.
I'm afraid even if we pass the exam, we will
hardly have a chance to show our abilities.
Talent is not judged by appearance.
Men and women are equal.
His Majesty overrode all objections
and reopened the Imperial Exam for Women.
His desire to recruit talent is evident.
When you enter the court in the future,
as long as I am here,
I will certainly back you up.
Sir, you are indeed a virtuous chancellor,
seeking benefits for the people,
paving paths for the humble,
and also speaking for women.
You're much more upright than Lord Xu.
But he has a deep foundation in the court
and holds the power of four ministries.
I truly feel indignant for you.
But I have never ever cared about power.
I have been loyal to His Majesty.
Even if His Majesty
entrusted all six ministries to Lord Xu,
I would not mind.
Sadly, His Majesty has ascended the throne,
yet the whole nation
knows only the virtue of Lord Xu,
but not the wisdom of His Majesty.
People all say a virtuous chancellor is rare.
And you're the only virtuous chancellor.
I will assist His Majesty
and create a new situation.
And then, women can also
hold their heads high in the court.
We will keep your teaching
in mind.
[Imperial Examination Hall]
Zhao Chun Nuan.
Yes.
Xie Yun Xi.
Meng, did you see that?
She just took a whole box of ink.
Are you here to accompany me
or to watch the fun?
Of course, I'm here to root for you.
Last night, I dreamed
that you topped the candidate list.
I was so happy and woke up laughing.
Please, Fu Zhi.
After that, I couldn't fall asleep.
So I just got up
and made you apricot skin cakes.
They're right here, and you...
I forgot to bring them.
I'll eat them after the exam.
Meng Ting Hui.
Yes.
Go back and wait for me.
I'll be waiting right here.
I won't go anywhere.
Meng, I have confidence in you.
You are the best in my eyes.
Don't be nervous.
Provincial Exam is easy for you.
You'll ace it.
Fu Zhi.
If you keep talking, I'll get dizzy.
I'll keep my mouth shut.
Meng Ting Hui.
Meng.
The Provincial Exam begins.
[Capital Boundary]
We've reached the capital boundary.
Your Majesty.
Return to the palace immediately.
Yes.
Keep up.
Your Majesty.
I have been waiting here for a long time.
Thank you.
[Shazhou]
Today, His Majesty will end his seclusion.
It's already noon.
Why hasn't His Majesty shown up yet?
It's quite strange. Even Lord Gu hasn't come.
Insolent!
How dare you make noise
before the Sacred Ancestral Hall!
It's such an important event,
and you're actually late!
What a disgrace!
I'm sorry, Lord Xu.
Last night,
the scouts saw His Majesty return.
Could it be...
His Majesty has ended his seclusion!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
May Your Majesty be blessed.
All of you, rise.
Lord Xu,
you have more white hair above your ears.
It seems during my ten days of seclusion,
you've worked very hard
in managing state affairs.
I do what I should do.
I do trivial things,
while Your Majesty thought of
how to govern the country.
Do you know what I've gotten?
I have had the honor
of serving three Emperors,
and I have some insights into court affairs.
I guess
that Your Majesty
has read the governing strategies
left by the late Emperor.
Very smart of you, Lord Xu.
You truly understand me.
Your Majesty, there is an urgent report.
Please review it, Your Majesty.
This matter is of great importance.
Chief Eunuch You,
lead the ministers to the main hall and wait.
Gu Qin and I will be there later.
Yes.
How dare you snore here! What a disgrace!
It's already very late.
I've drunk too much tea.
When will His Majesty arrive?
My lords, please be patient.
His Majesty will be here soon.
Lord Xu.
His Majesty is considerate of your old age
and specially prepared a chair for you.
Gu Qin, what did you talk
with His Majesty about?
His Majesty arrives.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
All of you have worked late into the night.
Thank you for your hard work.
When I was in ten-day seclusion,
Lord Xu managed the state affairs.
I have specially prepared a generous gift.
Get it in!
[Capable Minister of State]
What does Your Majesty mean by this?
Do you know
that your trusted man, Ding Chong,
used the plaque personally inscribed by you
as a protective talisman,
cheated and oppressed the people in Shazhou,
and acted tyrannically?
Your Majesty, Ding Chong told me personally
that he has been shielded
by Lord Xu all these years.
[Testimony of Magistrate Wang in Shazhou]
This is his criminal evidence.
Absurd!
Official-mafia collusion,
selling military equipment?
I know nothing about Ding Chong's actions!
And I've never shielded him.
Wasn't his plaque inscribed by you?
But I can tell
this is indeed your handwriting.
Your Majesty.
Lord Xu's men are spread
throughout the Ning Empire.
Inevitably,
corrupt officials exploit his inscriptions,
and this is not what Lord Xu wants.
Moreover, Shazhou is remote,
and Lord Xu always works very hard
for our nation.
Ding Chong's acts of deception
have nothing to do with Lord Xu.
Your Majesty,
I'm in charge of the Ministry of War.
Ding Chong, a treacherous guy,
made a mistake at work.
As his leader,
I'm to blame for my negligence.
It has nothing to do with Lord Xu.
I merely asked one question.
You all defended him.
Is it that I am wrong,
or that Lord Xu cannot be questioned?
Your Majesty, I've served three Emperors.
I swear I'm loyal to our nation.
One of my legs was injured by Zhongwan people
while I tried to protect the late Emperor,
affecting my walking.
I rely on my absolute loyalty
and numerous achievements
to earn the respect of all officials.
Your Majesty, when you were in Shazhou,
I don't know who deceived you,
or what slanderous whispers you heard
that made Your Majesty so dissatisfied
and suspicious of me.
What are you talking about?
I have been in seclusion for ten days
in the Sacred Ancestral Hall.
I tried to figure out how to govern.
When did I go to Shazhou?
It seems that Your Majesty
learned quite a bit about lying
in a remote place.
I remember I did go to Shazhou ten years ago.
Are you perhaps confusing old memories?
I have a witness.
- Where is the witness?
- Shen Zhi Shu.
Zhi Shu, have you been to Shazhou?
Yes, Your Majesty.
I was ordered by Your Majesty
to inspect Shazhou
and witnessed the chaos there
with my own eyes.
I've brought back evidence
against Ding Chong and others.
How dare you, Shen Zhi Shu!
That night in the Sacred Ancestral Hall,
you impersonated His Majesty,
and it was I who drove you to Shazhou
to bring His Majesty back.
Lord Xu, watch your words.
Breaking into the Sacred Ancestral Hall
is a grave crime.
You don't have to
add another crime on yourself
just to frame me and Shen Zhi Shu.
Your Majesty, please calm down.
Lord Xu is old,
and it's inevitable to misremember something.
So, Your Majesty set up a trap for me?
That's not true, Lord Xu.
Your Majesty,
I've investigated for a long time
and finally obtained solid evidence.
Wang Qi, the Military Governor of Shazhou,
disregarded military regulations.
Without General Gao Meng's knowledge,
he colluded with Liu Ren,
the Minister of War,
to embezzle 300,000 taels of military funds.
Wang Qi and Gao Meng are now waiting outside.
They can confront Mr. Liu right now
to clarify the facts.
- Summon them.
- Your Majesty, I'm guilty.
Your Majesty.
I made a mistake.
I'm guilty.
I beg Your Majesty for mercy.
Your Majesty, show mercy!
Lord Xu.
Liu Ren held a key position,
but colluded with a border general,
committed corruption,
and affected military affairs.
Now with both witnesses
and material evidence,
how should he be dealt with
according to the law?
Your Majesty,
according to the Laws of Ning Empire,
he should be flogged 100 times
and dismissed from office.
And all his property shall be confiscated.
But considering Liu Ren has worked
for many years--
Approved.
Do as Lord Xu suggested.
Immediately dismiss Liu Ren and punish him.
Wang Qi, as Military Governor,
sold military equipment
and bribed court officials.
He shall be sentenced to immediate execution.
Although Gao Meng is not mainly involved,
he cannot escape responsibility
for poor supervision
and is demoted by one rank.
He will temporarily remain in the army
to redeem himself by good service.
All military officials involved in this case
should be strictly investigated
with no leniency.
Your Majesty.
The position of Minister of War is crucial.
It cannot be vacant.
Pei Jing He, the Left Assistant Minister
of the Ministry of War,
is a capable man,
who was selected through the Imperial Exam.
But he was ostracized
because he
opposed Liu Ren's autocratic actions.
He was sent
to a nominal post like military supervisor,
without real power.
Immediately summon him back
to temporarily serve as the Minister of War.
Your Majesty,
this position carries great responsibility.
Such a hasty appointment may be improper.
Then let Gu Qin personally supervise it.
Just give rewards for merits
and punishments for faults.
I will do my best
and live up to Your Majesty's trust.
Good.
It is settled then.
Listen, all of you,
exercise more to keep energetic.
After all, you'll work late often.
Your Majesty.
Farewell, Your Majesty.
[Porridge distribution]
Ms. Yan's good friend, Meng Ting Hui,
got first place in the Provincial Exam.
To celebrate it,
we'll give free porridge for three days.
There's enough for everyone. Don't worry.
Here.
Take it easy.
No rush. Everyone will get some.
[Cold medicine]
The weather is cold,
so Ms. Yan offers everyone cold medicine.
Get some to avoid catching a cold.
- Here, take it.
- What a great person!
Thank you.
Father.
Be careful.
It's Meng Ting Hui who got first place,
not you.
Why are you celebrating for her?
It's disgraceful. I'm ashamed of you.
Come back with me.
Now that Bofeng is profitable,
I can do whatever I want.
When spring comes,
I will accompany Meng to Metropolitan Exam.
I'll go with her to the capital
to extend my business.
You will actually go to the capital with her!
You're out of your mind!
I'm very disappointed in you.
My dear!
Although Fu Zhi is a girl,
she has her own ideas.
Don't listen to those old women's rumors
that no man wants a woman working outside.
Even if Fu Zhi never marries,
we can afford to support her.
Not marry?
Is she going to hang around
with Meng Ting Hui for life?
Children's marriage is arranged by parents.
So I'll decide who she marries.
Fu Zhi.
I'll talk to your father about your marriage.
Don't be angry with him anymore.
My dear.
- My dear.
Are you alright?
I fell accidentally. It's not Fu Zhi's fault.
After all these years,
your ways of framing others haven't changed.
You!
Meng.
Meng Ting Hui.
How dare you stop me!
- I'm warning you!
- I...
I'm already the Jieyuan.
I don't need to bow even to the Governor.
If you slap me,
aren't you afraid all people in Shazhou
will talk about your rude action?
I can do nothing with you,
but can't I discipline my own daughter?
Someone, take Fu Zhi back!
- Meng.
- Hold on.
I've told the interim inspector of Shazhou
about your selfless decisions.
To celebrate the exam results,
you'll give porridge for three days.
And you've allowed your daughter
to go to the capital with me.
This is utter nonsense!
By order of the inspector,
we congratulate Miss Meng on your success.
Thank you very much.
The inspector presents the Yan family
with a banner of Honored Family
to commend their kindness.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Meng Ting Hui.
You won.
Thank you, Mrs. Yan.
Please tell the inspector
that Mrs. Yan decided
- to copy scriptures 1,000 times--
- 10,000 times.
No, 10,000 times, for me and Fu Zhi
to pray for a smooth journey to the capital.
Nonsense!
[Honored Family]
Thank you, Mr. Yan.
Thank you for your kindness.
Meng, I'm so lucky!
I can go to the capital with you!
I asked the inspector
to send the banner in advance.
I knew your father and stepmother
would try to stop you.
Meng, you're so good to me!
I'm so lucky to meet you.
People are watching.
Xiang.
I brought you
your favorite apricot skin cakes.
I miss you so much.
I miss you holding me in the cage.
[Tomb of Xiang]
We kept each other warm.
I miss you playing the flute for me.
You taught me your favorite tune.
That place was like hell,
but you were there.
Wherever you were was my home.
Xiang.
I hate that I was too weak.
I hate that I couldn't protect you back then.
Ting Hui.
You must escape from here.
As far as possible.
Xiang, hold on!
We will definitely escape from here.
We will definitely survive.
Xiang.
Xiang, say something.
What's wrong? Don't scare me.
Xiang.
Hold on, Xiang.
You brat!
How dare you mess with me!
Both of you just die!
Finish her off!
Xiang.
Shazhou has already changed now.
Those evil people
finally got their retribution.
Xiang.
I have never forgotten the promise
between us.
[Jieyuan of Shazhou]
Look.
I went to a Women's Academy.
I got first place in the Provincial Exam.
I'm about to go to the capital
to take the Metropolitan Exam.
I hear the palace walls there are very high,
and the palace is very big.
But there must be a place
to fulfill our shared aspirations.
[Jieyuan of Shazhou]
I will be a court official.
[Tomb of Xiang]
I must make myself strong.
I will protect Fu Zhi.
I will protect the people around me.
I will make our nation a place
where no one can trample on others at will.
I will let people like you and me
be bathed in the bright light.
Ting Hui.
Walk toward the light.
You must survive.
Xiang.
I'm afraid
I won't be able to visit you for a long time.
If you miss me,
please come to my dreams often.
I hear the capital is very damp,
so I brought you
a moisture-proof rhino horn pillow.
Fu Zhi, are you accompanying me
to the exam or moving house?
Meng.
We are new in the capital,
so I must make sure you're comfortable there.
Meng, I'm ready. Let's set off.
So ostentatious.
Aren't you afraid of bandits on the way?
[Metropolitan Exam Permit]
We have a shield.
Unless those bandits are tired of living,
they won't dare rob a top candidate
in the Provincial Exam.
I must make sure
my most beloved Meng leaves Shazhou
- in an impressive way.
- It'll be a long trip.
Don't worry.
Nobody will block your way to the capital.
We will surely arrive smoothly.
Capital, we're coming!
We're coming!
[Metropolitan Exam Permit]
Come back safely.
Your Majesty.
Here is what you want.
How so?
The list of successful candidates
is the key for Your Majesty
to defeat Lord Xu, right?
[List of candidates]
Not bad.
Shen Zhi Li got first place in the capital.
Of course,
with the bloodline of our Shen family.
You didn't take the exam, yet she did.
Don't you feel ashamed?
Exactly.
Keep your mouth shut.
Meng Ting Hui?
She actually got first place in Shazhou!
You mean Miss Meng
who solved the case with you in Shazhou?
A tough person
should play a key role.
Xu Ting's men are spread
throughout the six ministries.
The Imperial Exam is a good opportunity
for me to select useful people.
This time,
I'll definitely defeat that old fool.
Here's her chance.
Let's see how she takes it to soar high.
The shops here are busier
than those in Shazhou.
We must walk around later.
I've long heard
about the capital's prosperity.
Now I realize
I just learned a little about it from books.
Fu Zhi.
I hear the Huiyin House is
on this Changle Street.
Its owner is exactly Situ Xue.
How do you know?
Without thorough preparation,
how could I impersonate her well?
Capital, we've really made it!
My name is Yan Fu Zhi.
Her name is Meng Ting Hui.
Capital, here we come!
People are watching.
Welcome!
Stop!
Welcome, both of you!
Shun.
Come on in, and may you succeed.
[Come on in, and May You Succeed]
Listen up, Madam.
This is the Jieyuan from Shazhou!
What a surprise!
It's an honor to have you here!
My guests are all female candidates
for the Metropolitan Exam.
There's only one best room left.
Shun, show the honored guest inside.
- Come on in, please.
Don't forget my tavern
if you pass the exam.
[Chunman House]
Be careful!
To the Huxiao Gang!
To the gang leader!
The gang will become stronger!
Buddies work together!
Sir, the goods have arrived.